A Finding Aid to the Harold Weston Papers, 1894-1978, bulk 1912-1972, in the Archives of American Art AAA.westharo
Archives of American Art
- Writings and Notes, 1912-1975; Series 7; (Box 13-14; 0.6 linear feet)
  - By Others (Box 14)
    - "The Artist Sees Differently", by Duncan Phillips, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - "Illustration, Why Taboo?", Phillips Gallery, circa 1932 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - "How I Became What I Am", by Barbara Weston, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - "News Osterreich", by Unknown, 1960 October 5 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Poetry by Weston, to Helen Babbott, 1921 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Poetry by Weston, with Corrections, circa 1921; (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 20-21)
  - Poetry by Faith Weston, circa 1920s (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Academic Papers and Notes, 1912-1916; (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 23-24)
  - Annotated Postcards, circa 1950s (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Philadelphia Ethical Society Anniversary Speech by Weston, 1955 April 24 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Speech Notes, Illustrated Talks on Persia, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Speech Notes, Drafts, 1933-1969 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Speech Notes, General, 1950s-1960s (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Notes, Diary by Harold Weston, circa 1912-1917 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Notes, Day Diary by Faith Weston, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Notes, Concerning Middle East and World War I, 1917 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Notes, From Europe, circa 1957 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Notes, General, circa 1920s-1960s; (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 34-35)
  - Notes, Faith Weston, circa 1975 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Memorials to Weston, 1941-1954 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - "Leaves from a Scrapbook,", 1941-1954 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Lists, circa 1940s (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Lists, Works of Art, circa 1920s-1950s; (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 40-41)
- Artworks and Artifacts, circa 1917-1967; Series 8; (Box 14, 21; 0.6 linear feet)
  Artwork by Harold Weston include a bookplate, one etching, sketches and watercolors, including several of Baghdad during World War I, and two woodcuts, including a 1924 holiday card. There are also copperplates of "Shroud" and Building the United Nations, which were used in the Harvard Alumni Bulletin, as well as unidentified sketches by others.
  - Bookplate, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Copperplate, "Shroud,", circa 1950s; (See also Box 21) (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - Copperplate, "Building of the United Nations,", circa 1957; (See also Box 21) (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Etching, circa 1960s (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Illustrated Invitation, circa 1917 (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - Sketches, Baghdad in World War I, circa 1918 (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Sketches, Bedowin, circa 1918 (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Sketches, General, circa 1920s-1950s; (3 folders) (Box 14, Folder 49-51)
  - Sketches, Watercolor, circa 1920s-1950s; (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 52-53)
  - Woodcut, Baghdad, [1966] (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - Woodcut, Holiday Card, 1924 (Box 14, Folder 55)
  - Sketches and Etching, not by Weston, 1924-1967 (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - Oversized Copperplates, circa 1950s; (From Box 14, Folder 43-44) (Box 21)
- Printed Material, circa 1900-1978; Series 9; (Box 15-18, 38; 2.5 linear feet)
  Printed materials include art related publications and magazines, news clippings on many topics, exhibition announcements and catalogs, guides and maps from the Middle East, Harvard and Haverford School publications, materials concerning the production of Henry IV at Harvard for which Weston designed the sets, invitations and programs, materials depicting illustrations by Weston, and others, and a Royal Air Force guide to describing aerial photographs from 1918 entitled Notes on Aerial Photogrpahy, Part II.
  - Admission Tickets, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 57)
  - Art Related Publications, circa 1950s (Box 14, Folder 58)
  - Associations Materials, Various, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 14, Folder 59)
  - Blank Postcards, circa 1920s-1950s; (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 60-61)
  - Calendars, 1960s; (See also Box 38) (Box 14, Folder 62)
  - Clippings (Box 14)
    - Exhibitions, 1920s-1970s (Box 14, Folder 63)
    - French Publications, circa 1922 (Box 14, Folder 64)
    - Government Affiliations, 1950s-1960s (Box 14, Folder 65)
    - Henry IV, 1916 (Box 14, Folder 66)
    - The Nation, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 67)
    - The New Republic, 1920-1921 (Box 14, Folder 68)
  - Clippings (Box 15)
    - Travels, 1916-1920; (3 folders) (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
    - Studies for Sculpture, circa 1920s (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - World Magazine, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - General, About Weston, 1920-1972; (6 folders) (Box 15, Folder 6-11)
    - General, Weston's Art, 1920s-1950s (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - General, Art Related, 1950s-1960s (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - General, Not About Weston, 1940s-1970s; (2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 14-15)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1922-1976; (2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 16-17)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1922-1976; (8 folders) (Box 15, Folder 18-25)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1922-1976; (7 folders) (Box 16, Folder 1-7)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, Miscellaneous, 1920s-1960s; (4 folders) (Box 16, Folder 8-11)
  - Exhibition Reviews, circa 1925-1935 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Foreign Publications about Weston, 1930-1933 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Gallery Tags, 1925-1958 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Guide Maps of the Middle East, circa 1900-1919 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Harvard Alumni Materials, 1952-1971 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Harvard Lampoon Issues, 1911-1916 (Box 16, Folder 17-20)
  - Harvard Lampoon, 1876-1951--75th Anniversary, circa 1951 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Haverford School Quarterly, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Henry IV, Programs, 1916 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Henry IV, Weston's Copy with Notes, circa 1916 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Invitations and Programs, 1955-1969 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Invitations for Weston's Talks, 1920-circa 1935 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Illustrated by Weston, 1914-1918 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Magazines, Articles on Weston, 1930-1939 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, Art Related, 1942-1966 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets, 1950s-1966 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Phillips Memorial Gallery Publications, 1930-1931 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Press Releases, 1950s (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Reproductions of Works of Art by Weston, 1920s-1970s; (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 6-7)
  - Reproductions of Works of Art Not by Weston, 1920s-1960s; (3 folders) (Box 17, Folder 8-10)
  - School Seals, circa 1908-1916 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Asia: The American Magazine on the Orient, 1920 October (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Color Mediums, circa 1910s (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Harold Weston, by Ben Wolf, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Iraq--Photographic Slides, by Oliver F. Butler, circa 1919 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Language of Design, by C. Law Watkins, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Magazine of Art, 1939 January (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - National Geographic, 1921 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - New Forces in American Art, circa 1938 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Notes on Aerial Photography, Part II, 1918 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Painters and Sculptors and Modern Activity, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Problems of Authenticity in American Art, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Oversized Calendars, 1960s; (From Box 14, Folder 62) (Box 38)
- Scrapbooks, circa 1963-1977; Series 10; (Box 17-18; 0.5 linear feet)
  Two scrapbooks were compiled by Faith Weston about Harold. The first contains materials mostly from the IAPA conference in 1963 which includes a photograph of and best wishes from President John F. Kennedy for the success of the IAPA conference. The second scrapbook consists primarily of clippings about Harold Weston's career as a painter. It was created in 1977 and contains materials dating from 1917 to 1977.
  Materials have been removed from their binders but kept in original order.
  - Scrapbook 1 (Box 17)
    - Front Cover, circa 1963 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Loose Documents Tucked into Scrapbook, circa 1963 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Pages 1-4, circa 1963 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Pages 5-8, circa 1963 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Pages 9-12, circa 1963 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Pages 13-16, circa 1963 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Pages 17-20, circa 1963 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Pages 21-24, circa 1963 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Pages 25-28, circa 1963 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Pages 29-32, circa 1963 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Pages 33-36, circa 1963 (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - Binder Covers, circa 1963 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Scrapbook 2 (Box 18)
    - Introduction Notes by Faith Weston, 1977 November 18 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Volume 1--1917-1927, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Volume 2--1927-1931, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Volume 3--1931-1934, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Volume 4--1934-1938, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Volume 5--1938-1952, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Volume 6--1977 July 5, (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 7-8)
    - Volume 7--Added Inserts, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Volume 8--Added Inserts, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Photographs, circa 1900-1975; Series 11; (Box 18-20, 22-36, 38; 4.8 linear feet)
  This series includes Harold Weston's personal photographs, photographs of works of art, travel photos, and negatives. Personal photographs are of Weston, his family and friends, exhibitions, and his studio. Images of Weston's studio were taken by Faith in 1975 and depict the space as he left it before his death. Also found is a portrait of Weston's artist friend, Dorothy Paris. Travel photgraphs are of France, the Adirondacks, and cities throughout the Middle East including locations in present day Iraq, Iran, India. Photographs of works of art include Weston's paintings and sculpture as well as works of art not by Weston but owned by the family or displayed in their home in France.
  Also found are 122 glass plate negatives of works of art painted by Weston in France between 1926-1930. Although Faith Weston supplied a list of works included in each box, it is unlikely that the order was maintained over the years. There are approximately one hundred lantern slides of scenes and people throughout the Middle East, most likely used by Weston in lectures, speeches, and talks.
  Another set of glass plate negatives belonged to S.B. Weston, Harold's father, and are Adirondack scenes. Most of the plates are outdoor images although there is one photo of Harold Weston and his brother Carl as children. Although most of the slides are unlabeled, whenever possible an attempt has been made to identify them on the slide sleeve.
  All glass plates and lantern slides have been removed from their original cases, but the cases have been saved in in Boxes 19 and 22. An attempt has been made to identify each of the lantern slides and these are grouped together by city or "scenes" such as agriculture or caravaning.
  Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers. All original glass plate negative sleeves are in Box 23 and have been assigned numbers corresponding to their glass plate negative. Sleeves are noted '#B' and glass plates are noted '#A'.
  - of the Artist, circa 1916-1952 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - of Weston's Studio, 1975 March 6 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - of Weston, Family and Friends, 1919-circa 1940s (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - of Weston and Friends, circa 1918 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - of Weston and Others, 1938, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - of Dorothy Paris, circa 1920s (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - "Summer, 1919," (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Exibitions, General, circa 1947-1970s (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Installations at St. Lawrence University, 1970 March 3 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Harold Weston's Snow Shoes, 1940 December (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Adirondacks, circa 1920 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - YMCA Camp Photo [?], circa 1919 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - France, Spain, and North Africa, circa 1926; (4 folders) (Box 18, Folder 23-26)
  - India, circa 1919 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Hamadan, Iran, circa 1917-1919 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Baghdad, Crowds and People, circa 1917-1919 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Iraq and "Persia", circa 1917-1919; (See also Box 38; 4 folders) (Box 18, Folder 30-33)
  - Baghdad, Scenes, circa 1917-1919; (7 folders) (Box 18, Folder 34-39)
  - List of Middle East Photographs, circa 1919 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Works of Art (Box 18)
    - Self-Portraits, circa 1922-1930s (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - Portrait of Faith Weston, 1923 (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - Portraits of Unidentified Figures, circa 1920s-1940s; (5 folders) (Box 18, Folder 43-47)
    - Landscapes Scenes, circa 1920s-1960s; (4 folders) (Box 18, Folder 48-51)
  - Works of Art (Box 20)
    - Landscapes Scenes, circa 1922-1960s (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
    - Paintings, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Sculpture, 1924 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Sculpture, Now Destroyed, circa 1923 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Sculpture, Terracotta, circa 1920s (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Stone Series, circa 1971 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - General, circa 1920s-1960s; (3 folders) (Box 20, Folder 8-10)
    - By Others, Owned by Weston, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Negatives, circa 1950s-1960s; (2 folders) (Box 20, Folder 12-13)
    - By Others, circa 1920s-1950 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Works of Art (Box 23)
    - Faith Weston's List of Works in Glass Plate Negative Boxes, circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Sleeves for Glass Plate Negatives, Miscellaneous Works of Art, circa 1920s (Box 23, Folder 2)
      [Corresponding glass plate negatives housed in Boxes 24-25]
    - Sleeve for Glass Plate Negatives, 1920 Christmas Greeting (Box 23, Folder 3)
      [Corresponding glass plate negative housed in Box 24]
    - Sleeve for Glass Plate Negatives, Baghdad, Portrait of H. Weston, circa 1918 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Sleeve for Glass Plate Negatives, S. Burns Weston, circa 1900 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      [Corresponding glass plate negatives housed in Box 26]
  - Glass Plate Negatives of Works of Art (Box 24)
    - Box 1, Slides 86-87, 91, 93, 96, 98, 123, 125, 128-129, circa 1920s (Box 24)
      (10 glass plate negatives)
    - Box 2, Slides 30, 32, 34, 35-37, 38, 76, 121, circa 1920s (Box 24)
      (9 glass plate negatives)
    - Box 3, Slides 75, 81, 95, 118, 124, 127, 130, circa 1920s (Box 24)
      (7 glass plate negatives)
    - Box 4, Slides 25, 42-43, 46, 51, 61, 67, 69, 72, 77-78, 84, 92, circa 1920s (Box 24)
      (13 glass plate negatives)
    - Box 5, Slides 21, 23-24, 26, 27-29, 73, 119, 172, circa 1920s (Box 24)
    - Box 6, Slides 40-41, 44-45, 62, 64, 70, 74, 79-80, 90, 97, circa 1920s (Box 24)
      (12 glass plate negatives)
    - Box 7, Slides 39, 48-50, 52, 60, 63, 82, 85, 88, 94, 122, 133, circa 1920s (Box 24)
    - Box 8, Slides 19, 20-22, 131, circa 1920s (Box 24)
      (4 glass plate negatives)
    - Miscellaneous Works of Art, circa 1920 (Box 24)
      (5 glass plate negatives)
    - 1920 Holiday Greeting (Box 24)
      (1 glass plate negative)
  - Glass Plate Negatives of Works of Art (Box 25)
    - Box 9, Slides 1-4, 5-8, 9-12, 13-15, circa 1920s (Box 25)
      (14 glass plate negatives)
    - Box 10, Slides 16-18, 47, 53-55, 56-58, circa 1920s (Box 25)
    - Box 11, Slides 100-101, 103-104, 105-107, 109, circa 1920s (Box 25)
      (8 glass plate negatives)
    - Box 12, Slides 102, 102, 110-117, 134-135, circa 1920s (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous Works of Art, circa 1920s (Box 25)
  - Glass Plate Negatives, Baghdad (Box 24)
    - Portrait of Harold Weston, Soldier, circa 1918 (Box 24)
  - Glass Plate Negatives, Baghdad (Box 26)
    - Baghdad Art Club, Paintings and Drawings, circa 1918 (Box 26)
      (15 glass plate negatives)
    - Baghdad Scenes, circa 1918 (Box 26)
      (16 glass plate negatives)
    - Middle East Scenes, circa 1918 (Box 26)
  - Glass Plate Negatives, S. Burns Weston, circa 1900 (Box 26)
    - Gill Brook, circa 1900 (Box 26)
      (2 glass plate negatives)
    - Icy Brook, circa 1900 (Box 26)
      (17 glass plate negatives)
    - People, circa 1900 (Box 26)
      (Includes Carl & Harold Weston, Wesley Otis, and Unidentified People; 4 glass plate negatives)
    - St. Hubert's Inn, circa 1900 (Box 26)
    - Unidentified Outdoors, circa 1900 (Box 26)
    - Upper Chapel Brook, circa 1900 (Box 26)
      (6 glass plate negatives)
  - Lantern Slides, Middle East (Box 27)
    - Baghdad Scenes, circa 1920; (2 folders) (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
    - Baghdad Art Club, circa 1920 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Lantern Slides, Middle East (Box 28)
    - Portraits and Group Photos in Middle East, circa 1920; (3 folders) (Box 28, Folder 1-3)
  - Lantern Slides, Middle East (Box 29)
    - Works of Art, Westons and Inidentified, circa 1920 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Agricultural Scenes, circa 1920; (2 folders) (Box 29, Folder 2-3)
  - Lantern Slides, Middle East (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous Photos, circa 1920 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Esfahan Scenes, circa 1920; (2 folders) (Box 30, Folder 2-3)
  - Lantern Slides, Middle East (Box 31)
    - Esfahan Scenes, circa 1920 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Kurdistan Scenes, circa 1920; (2 folders) (Box 31, Folder 2-3)
  - Lantern Slides, Middle East (Box 32)
    - Shiraz Scenes, circa 1920 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Persepolis Scenes, circa 1920 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Hamadan Scenes, circa 1920 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Lantern Slides, Middle East (Box 33)
    - Caravaning Scenes, circa 1920 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Ruins and Ancient Sites, circa 1920; (2 folders) (Box 33, Folder 2-3)
  - Lantern Slides, Middle East (Box 34)
    - Basrah and Caspian Region Scenes, circa 1920 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Teheran and British Army Scenes, circa 1920 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Scenes, circa 1920 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Lantern Slides, Middle East (Box 35)
    - Naqsh-e-Rustam and Yezdikhast Scenes, circa 1920 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Tigris River Scenes, circa 1920 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous City Scenes, circa 1920 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Lantern Slides, Middle East (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous Scenes, circa 1920 (Box 36, Folder 1-3)
  - Oversized Photo of Persepolis Ruins, circa 1920; (From Box 18, Folder 30) (Box 38)
  - Lantern Slides Cases (Box 19)
  - Glass Plate Negative Boxes (Box 22)